(upbeat music)
- Hello, English learners.
Welcome back to English Pot.
My name is Marco.
- And I'm Erica.
- And we're bringing you a
very advanced lesson today.
- That's right.
We're talking about another
business topic, aren't we?
- It's a topic that's
kind of popular these
days all about efficiency
and reducing costs.
So we're gonna be talking
about the just in time philosophy.
- I don't know much about this philosophy.
So good thing we've got Marco here.
- Well, what we are gonna be
looking at is not really in depth.
- We're just gonna be
looking at some basic points
of what a just in time philosophy
would be like in a company.
- But what we're really gonna be looking at
is the language to do
with this philosophy, right?
- Exactly.
We're gonna be looking
at some technical terms
and some other useful
phrases that you can use
when we were talking
in a business setting.
- Okay, well, why don't we get
started with the language then?
- Okay, let's take a look
at vocabulary preview.
- Vocabulary preview.
- On vocabulary preview today,
we have the word lead time.
- Lead time.
- Well, EAD lead, lead time.
- Right, like lead.
This is something that
factories usually would use.
- Yeah, yeah.
I guess lead time is the
time in between point A
and point B on a
production schedule, right?
- Right, so you could have, for
example, production lead time.
- So that's the time between when you make
an order and when the product is finished.
- Exactly, and you could
also have delivery lead time.
- So the time between
when you place an order
and when the product
gets delivered to you.
- So depending on the companies you have
differently times somewhere three days,
or there are five days,
or there are 45 days.
- And we at EnglishPod have a two
week lead time for our podcast, right?
- But our delivery lead
time is every other day.
- That's true.
- Nice.
Okay, that's all we're
gonna be previewing today.
So why don't we just listen to the dialogue
and then we'll come
back and explain some of
these tricky vocabulary
words that we'll see.
(upbeat music)
- I called this meeting today in order
to discuss our manufacturing plan.
As I'm sure you're all aware with the credit
crunch and the global financial crisis,
we're obligated to look for more cost
efficient ways of producing our goods.
We don't want to have to
be looking at redundancies.
So we've outlined a brief plan to
implement the just in time philosophy.
We have two basic points
that we want to focus on.
First of all, we want to
reduce our lead time.
Why would we want to do that?
I think this is not an area that
really needs to be walked on.
Well, we want to reduce production
and delivery lead times
for better overall efficiency.
- Right, production lead
times can be reduced by moving
workstations closer together,
reducing Q-length like for example,
reducing the number of
jobs waiting to be processed
at a given machine and
improving the coordination
and cooperation between
successive processes.
Delivery lead times can be reduced
through close cooperation with suppliers,
possibly by inducing
suppliers to locate closer to
the factory or working with
a faster shipping company.
- I see, that makes sense.
- The second point is
that we want to require
supplier quality assurance and
implement a zero defects quality program.
We currently have far too
many errors that lead to
defective items, and therefore,
they must be eliminated.
A quality control at the source
program must be implemented
to give workers personal responsibility
for the quality of the work they do
and the authority to stop production
when something goes wrong.
- I'm waiting on this one.
It's essential that we reduce these errors.
We've got two false suppliers
to reduce their mistakes.
- Exactly.
Well, let's look at how we're
going to put this plan into action.
First.
(upbeat music)
- Okay, so they're going to
implement just in time in their company.
- Yes, yeah, I guess they're putting
in some cost control measures.
So Marco, there's some
great language in here.
Why don't we look at it
now in language takeaway?
- Language takeaway.
- Okay, the first word today, reduntancies.
- Redundancies.
So this is kind of a strange word
because usually a redundancy
is when you're speaking, right?
- Yeah, maybe when you say
something that's already been said.
- Exactly.
You say something
that it has already been
said, but we also use
it in the business world.
- Right, and it comes from
the base word redundant, right?
- Okay.
- Meaning extra more than what's needed.
- So when a person or a
position is made redundant,
basically it means
they get laid off, right?
- Right, so redundancies
are a synonym of layoffs.
- Exactly.
- Okay. All right, let's take
a look at our next word.
Workstations.
- Workstations.
- So workstation can be
anything from your desk.
- Yeah, or maybe a workbench.
- A workbench.
- Or even a place on a production line.
- Right, so you're a certain
machine or something like that.
- Yeah, so basically a workstation
is the area where you work.
- Okay.
Okay, so you can say, can we get a new
workstation for the new team member?
- Or I could say, I want to move my
workstation closer to my employees.
- All right, so workstation.
Okay, let's take a look at our next word.
At a given machine.
- At a given machine.
- At a given.
- This is an interesting
way to say at any machine.
- Exactly.
- Okay.
- Yeah, given here is operating
exactly the same as here.
The word given is operating
exactly the same way as any.
- Yeah.
- Okay, so let's listen to
some examples of how we can
change it up a little bit and
we can use this given word.
- Example one, in this factory, how many
cars are in production at any given time?
- Example two.
- On any given day, about 40
million people use the internet.
- Example three.
- Air fighters have to be ready to attend
an emergency at any given moment.
- All right, so any given
time at any given moment?
- Yep.
Any given day.
- Okay, now let's take a
look at our last word today.
- Defective.
- So if something is defective.
- It has a problem with it.
- It has a problem.
- Yeah.
- We can say defective is an adjective.
- Right.
- Now on is defect.
- Defect.
- Yep.
- So if something has
a defect, it is defective.
- Right.
So for example, maybe
you produce chairs and
you make one and this
chair is missing a wheel.
- Okay.
So it's defective.
- Yes.
- The defect is the missing wheel.
- The defect is the...
- Okay.
So before we listen
to our dialogue again, I
want to take a look at this
phrase, I'm with you on this one.
- I'm with you on this one.
- So what is that?
- What does that mean exactly?
- I'm with you on this one.
- I agree with you.
- I agree with you on this point.
- Exactly.
- Okay.
So if you agree with
somebody on a certain point,
you would say, "Oh,
I'm with you on this one.
I agree with you.
" - Exactly.
- Okay.
So now let's listen to
our dialogue again and
we'll come back and talk a little bit more
about the history of this just in time.
- I called this meeting today in order to
discuss our manufacturing plan, as I'm sure
you're all aware with the credit
crunch and the global financial crisis.
We're obligated to look for more
cost-efficient ways of producing our goods.
We don't want to have to be
looking at redundancies, so we've
outlined a brief plan to implement
the just in time philosophy.
- We have two basic points
that we want to focus on.
First of all, we want to
reduce our lead time.
What do we want to do that?
I think this is not an area that
really needs to be walked home.
- Well, we want to reduce
production and deliver
lead times for better
overall efficiency.
- Right.
Production lead times
can be reduced by
moving workstations
closer together, reducing
Q-length, like for example,
reducing the number
of jobs waiting to be
processed at a given
machine, and improving the coordination and
cooperation between successive processes.
- Every lead times can be reduced through
close cooperation with suppliers, possibly
by inducing suppliers
to locate closer to factory,
or working with a
faster shipping company.
- I see.
That makes sense.
- The second point is
that we want to require
supplier quality assurance and
implement a zero defects quality program.
We currently have far
too many errors that
lead to defective items, and
therefore, they must be eliminated.
A quality control at the
source program must be
implemented to give
workers personal responsibility
for the quality of the
work they do, and the
authority to stop production
when something goes wrong.
- I'm waiting on this one.
It's essential that we reduce these errors.
We've got two false suppliers
to reduce their mistakes.
- Exactly.
Well, let's look at how we're
going to put this plan into action.
First.
- All right, so Marco,
I mentioned at the
beginning of the lesson
that I don't know much
about just in time, but
luckily you do, right?
- Yeah, I know a little bit about it.
- So, tell me a little bit
about where this philosophy
came from, what are
the origins of this idea?
- It actually became
really popular with
Toyota, and it was called
the Toyota production system.
So many people think
it's Japanese, but in
reality, the Japanese got
it from the United States.
It's a philosophy that
was thought up by Ford
Motor Company in order to
improve their production line.
But when the Japanese visited Ford Motor
Company, it wasn't fully implemented yet.
And oddly enough, they
found this philosophy
working already in a
piggy-wiggly wiggly.
- What's a piggy-wiggly?
- Piggy-wiggly was a chain of
grocery stores in the United States.
- Okay.
I'm not sure if they're still around, but
yeah, they were really big, and basically
piggy-wiggly-wiggly
was using this to improve
their whole system of shipping
and of stocking and everything.
- Okay, so how does it work?
- So basically what you
try to do is make your
processes more efficient, reduce the
amount of space you're using, et cetera.
And this was really
important for Japanese
because, of course, they
don't have that much
space in Japan to have this huge
warehouses like in other countries.
So what you're saying
is they're producing
goods just for the
time they need it, right?
- Exactly.
So trying to not be overstocked, or
have, like, a long lead time or something.
- Long lead times where you have to
keep something in a warehouse, exactly.
So that's why it's so efficient.
And also it's about improving
the efficiency between processes.
So what's sometimes called a bottleneck.
You can have really
good processes in the
beginning, but in the
end, maybe you have only
one workstation that's
taking all these orders
and everything gets bottled
up and it causes delays.
- So in the dialogue,
they want to implement
the just-in-time strategy as a
way of avoiding redundancies.
But it sounds to me like, actually, this
might cause redundancies sometimes.
- Well, yeah, sometimes it does.
Sometimes when you
make workstations more
efficient or when you
make all your processes
work more fluidly,
sometimes inevitably you will
have to lay off some
people that are redundant.
- Okay.
Have you ever worked in a company
where they've implemented just in time?
- No, actually, I've never really worked at
a place where this philosophy was working,
but I did use to work
at a place where we had
six sigma, which is a,
which is a little bit similar.
- Yeah.
- Well, I guess we'll need
a lesson on six sigma now.
- Yeah, we'll see if we
come up with a six sigma
and what it means, and
it's kind of interesting,
but we want to hear what you think.
- Yes, have you guys worked in a
place where they use just in time?
- Exactly, or if you
have any quality control
measures, or how does
your company avoid
having defective items
or defective services?
- So visit our website, englishpod.com,
and Marco and I are always
around to respond to your
comments and answer your questions.
- Exactly, so until
then, it's- - Goodbye.
(upbeat music)